This guy was banned from the Olympics,
even though he had the fifth fastest
time in the world. He was using running
blades, but by itself, that's not
illegal. The big question was, did he
have a correction, like eyeglasses for
shooting, which are allowed, or an
enhancement, like fins for swimming,
which are not allowed? So, they ran a
bunch of tests on Blake, and they said,
"Well, prosthetics don't use your body's
oxygen, but they're worse at rounding
corners, so it seems fair." But then,
they used a new rule, the mash rule,
which determined that Blake couldn't
compete because his running blades made
him taller than he would be naturally.
But Blake never had a height with legs
naturally. He was born without them.
They used other measurements of his body
to calculate his theoretical height,
ignoring that athletes often have odd
measurements. But they said he'd have to
retrain 6 in shorter, an impossible ask
so close to the Olympics. I don't agree
with it, but I understand. And these
questions are getting more tricky
[music] as tech gets better. So, do you
agree with it? Tell me in the comments,
and subscribe.